You’ve heard of Charles Darwin, right?
你听说过查尔斯・达尔文（Charles Darwin），对吧？
The celebrated scientist who proposed a theory of evolution.
那位提出了进化论的著名科学家。
You might have just about heard of Alfred Russel Wallace, who co-authored, with Darwin, the revolutionary work On the Origin of Species, published in 1859.
你可能也听说过阿尔弗雷德・拉塞尔・华莱士（Alfred Russel Wallace），他与达尔文共同撰写了1859年出版的具有颠覆性意义的著作《物种起源》（On the Origin of Species）。
But what about Patrick Matthew?
但是帕特里克・马修（Patrick Matthew）呢？
‘Patrick who?’ you might ask.
你可能会问：“帕特里克谁？”
Well, Darwin and Wallace got the fame but Matthew did the legwork too.
嗯，达尔文和华莱士声名远扬，但马修也做了不少基础工作（legwork跑腿外勤的工作）。
This British horticulturalist actually thought about evolution first, as Dr Mike Weale, geneticist at King’s College London, explains.
正如伦敦国王学院（King’s College London）的遗传学家迈克・韦尔（Mike Weale）博士所解释的，这位英国园艺学家实际上是最先思考进化问题的。
He says: "Matthew published a brief outline of the idea of species being able to change into other species through natural selection.
他说：“马修发表了一个简短概述（outline），是关于物种能够通过自然选择变成其他物种这一观点的。
And he did that 27 years before Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace.
而且他比达尔文和阿尔弗雷德・拉塞尔・华莱士早27年就做到了这一点。
And they recognized that he did so but other people since have simplified the story and tended to concentrate just on Darwin."
他们（达尔文和华莱士）也承认确实如此，但从那以后，其他人简化了这段历史，并且倾向于只关注达尔文。”
So Patrick Matthew's relative obscurity may simply be down to... us – the general public – wanting to simplify things.
所以帕特里克・马修相对默默无闻（obscurity）可能仅仅是因为我们——普罗大众——想要简化一些事情。
But Dr Patricia Fara, senior tutor at Clare College Cambridge, points out that Darwin's work might have received more attention because he had powerful friends.
但是剑桥大学克莱尔学院（Clare College Cambridge）的高级导师帕特里夏・法拉（Patricia Fara）博士指出，达尔文的作品之所以受到更多关注，可能是因为他那些有影响力的朋友们。
"He brought his allies on board", she says.
“他拉拢了他的盟友（allies），”她说。
The academic explains that "although he was publishing from his stronghold down in Kent, he had the most famous, most prominent members of the scientific society in Victorian times, who were pushing on his behalf.
这位学者解释说：“尽管他是在肯特郡（Kent）的大本营（有共同态度或信仰）发表著作，但他拥有维多利亚时代科学界最著名、最杰出的成员，这些人在为他造势。
Having a scientific theory being accepted is not just a matter of whether the theory’s right."
让一个科学理论被接受可不仅仅是理论是否正确的问题。”
Maybe it is time for us to remember Patrick Matthew, a pioneer of the story of survival through adaptation that is at the heart of evolution.
也许现在是我们记住帕特里克・马修的时候了，是他第一个提出适应环境才能生存这一进化论的核心理念。